[
    {
        "question": "What is the state flower of Alaska?",
        "answer": "Alpine forget-me-not -- The background of the Alaskan flag is in part inspired by the forget-me-not color."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country borders the Republic of Guinea-Bissau to the south and east?",
        "answer": "Guinea"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau has a coast on which ocean?",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bijagos Archipelago lie off which country`s mainland?",
        "answer": "Guinea-Bissau"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the `Wailing Wall`?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Australia`s highest mainland mountain?",
        "answer": "Mount Kosciuszko"
    },
    {
        "question": "Camp Lejeune Marine Corps Base is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river flows along the western boundary of New Jersey?",
        "answer": "Delaware River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What modern-day US state was inhabited by the Calusa Indians?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Cornhusker State`?",
        "answer": "Nebraska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Charleston is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "West Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What three states share a border with New Hampshire?",
        "answer": "Maine, Massachusetts and Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "Banjul is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "The Gambia"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what Gaelic word is `Dublin` derived?",
        "answer": "Dublind"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Armenia?",
        "answer": "Yerevan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Yerevan is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Armenia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was shoe manufacturer Reebok founded?",
        "answer": "Bolton, England"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sea lies at one end of the Great Wall of China?",
        "answer": "The Yellow Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What branch of the US military manages a white oak forest in Indiana?",
        "answer": "US Navy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has hosted the Wife Carrying World Championships since the competition`s founding in 1992?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state can you find George Vanderbilt`s extravagant Biltmore Estate?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is the only capital located on the Rhine River?",
        "answer": "Vaduz, Liechtenstein"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state`s flag has different images on the front and back?",
        "answer": "Oregon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague`s astronomical clock?",
        "answer": "The 12 Apostles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mountain range is home to the largest U.S. National Park?",
        "answer": "Saint Elias Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famous mountain peak is not part of a mountain range?",
        "answer": "Mt. Kilimanjaro"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which mountain range is the highest continuous paved road in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Rocky Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mountain range separates Siberia from the Gobi Desert?",
        "answer": "Altai Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "question": "Omaha, Kansas City, and Sioux City all lie on which river?",
        "answer": "Missouri River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Canadian territory that shares a land border with Alaska?",
        "answer": "Yukon Territory"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Hungary?",
        "answer": "Budapest"
    },
    {
        "question": "What California desert boasted the first solar power plant able to store heat, in 1996?",
        "answer": "Mojave Desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country has the largest number of citizens living within the Arctic Circle?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state capital city lies at the western edge of its state`s Bluegrass Region?",
        "answer": "Frankfort"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which three countries in the world do not use the metric system?",
        "answer": "Liberia, Myanmar and the U.S. -- They have not adopted the International System of Units (SI, or metric system) as their official system of weights and measures."
    },
    {
        "question": "Ilha da Queimada Grande Island is dominantly inhabited by which species of animal?",
        "answer": "Snakes -- The Brazilian island is so dangerous, it is illegal to visit. Researchers estimate that about five snakes per square meter live on the island."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country is it illegal to own just one guinea pig?",
        "answer": "Switzerland -- Guinea pigs are social animals by nature and require healthy interaction with others of their kind in order to be happy and maintain a good attitude."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country owns the island where most white-capped albatross nest?",
        "answer": "New Zealand -- Disappointment Island, part of the Auckland Islands, is the island where the birds nest. New Zealand owns the islands."
    },
    {
        "question": "On average, how often is the Eiffel Tower repainted?",
        "answer": "Every seven years -- The structure has been repainted 18 times, not always the same color though"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is nicknamed `The Waterfall Capital of the World`?",
        "answer": "Hamilton, Ontario, Canada -- According to Smithsonian Magazine, Hamilton holds the record for the most waterfalls within one city`s limits, with 156 separate falls."
    },
    {
        "question": "What currency was used in the Netherlands before the introduction of the Euro?",
        "answer": "Guilders"
    },
    {
        "question": "Of which country did F.W. de Klerk become president in 1989?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the `House of the Seven Gables` located?",
        "answer": "Salem"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state would you find the `House of the Seven Gables`?",
        "answer": "Massachusetts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river is Liverpool situated on?",
        "answer": "Mersey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Space Needle?",
        "answer": "Seattle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which large island?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. Lake has its own version of the Bermuda Triangle?",
        "answer": "Lake Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state`s tree is the American Holly?",
        "answer": "Delaware"
    }
]